#### **Personal Information**

Address: 3058 Villa Street

Los Alamos, NM 87544

Phone: Email: casey.alan.anderson@gmail.com

+1 (920) 858-8783

# Casey A. Anderson

https://www.linkedin.com/in/caseyalananderson

**Work Information** 

Address: MS-T086, P.O. Box 1663

Los Alamos, NM 87545 +1 (505) 667-5968

Phone: Email: casey\_a@lanl.gov

Engineer, scientist, researcher, and software developer with ten years experience involving scientific computing, critical thinking, and analytical problem solving. Publisher and presenter of results, mentor of students, leader in scientific organizations, and effective collaborator in diverse work environments.

## Professional Experience

## Los Alamos National Laboratory Los Alamos, New Mexico

Research Scientist 2017 - Present XTD-PRI, Primary Physics **Graduate Research Assistant** NEN-5, Systems Design & Analysis | ISR-1, Space Science & Applications 2016 - 2017

2011 - 2012 **Post Master's Research Assistant** *E-13, Advanced Engineering Analysis* 

2010 **Summer Intern** XCP-3, Monte Carlo Codes

## COMPUTATIONAL PHYSICS CODE DEVELOPMENT, PHYSICIST, TITANS ENROLLEE

- Gaining knowledge of primary physics, nuclear weapons systems, and the U.S. stockpile
- Software development in Python, C/C++, C#, Fortran, Matlab, Javascript, and HTML
- Developer of MCNP<sup>TM</sup>, the Common Modeling Framework (CMF), and the Nuclear Detection Figure of Merit (NDFOM) project, implementing features such as:
  - $\delta$ -ray production, correlated secondary particles, detector response functions, and multi-physics coupling to MCNP6
  - Full software testing (regression, unit, integration, validation) packages for the Continuous Integration of CMF
  - Automated analysis of detector systems, sources, configurations, and scenarios for NDFOM
- · Performing physics and engineering analysis of systems on the high performance computing systems at LANL
- Developing software using tools such as Git and BitBucket for version control and Jenkins-CI for software testing
- Mentoring students at the undergraduate and high-school level
- Presenting at conferences and publishing articles in their proceedings [Pubs: 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 11, 12, 13, 14]

# Medical College of Wisconsin Milwaukee, Wisconsin

2012 - 2016 | Graduate Research Assistant Department of Biophysics

#### RESEARCH IN TRANSLATIONAL MEDICINE AND MAGNETIC RESONANCE IMAGING

- Funded my graduate research by contributing to a successful R21 National Institute of Health research grant
- Patented a segmented reconstruction technique for artifact reduction in Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) [Pat: i.]
- · Performed data analytics on large imaging datasets seeking clinical applications and trends in our imaging technique
- · Interacted with patients, researched on animals, acquired hands-on laboratory experience, and collaborated with medical doctors while conducting clinical and pre-clinical research

## University of Wisconsin - Madison Madison, Wisconsin

2008 - 2011 | Student Research Assistant Department of Medical Physics 2010 - 2011 | Chapter President American Nuclear Society

## MEDICAL PHYSICS RESEARCH AND ORGANIZATIONAL MANAGEMENT

- · Researched methods for non-invasive Quality Assurance assessment of radioactive brachytherapy seeds
- Managed our student chapter of the American Nuclear Society (ANS) as chapter president

# TECHNICAL & PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

## Physics/Engineering

- Computational Physics
- Nuclear Weapons
- Modeling and Simulation
- Nuclear Engineering
- Signal and Image Processing
- Fourier Analysis
- Monte Carlo Methods
- Statistical Analysis
- Radiation Detectors
- Regularization Methods
- Lagrangian & Eularian Methods
- Computer Aided Engineering
- Finite Element Analysis

#### Software

- Linux / MacOS
- LATEX
- Matplotlib
- Jenkins-Cl
- Bitbucket
- Confluence
- MCNP
- Django
- Microsoft Office
- Abaqus/CAE
- PostgreSQL
- O FLAG

### **Programming**

- Python
- Git / Mercurial
- Version Control
- Continuous Integration
- Unit Testing
- Scripting/Bash
- Matlab
- Parallel Programming
- C/C++/C#
- Fortran
- SQL
- HTML/Javascript

### Other Skills

- Technical Writing
- Presentations
- High Performance Computing
- Group Collaboration
- Independent Work
- File Input/Output
- Student Mentoring
- Data Collection
- Data Analytics
- Data Visualization
- Validation & Verification
- Relational Databases
- Linux Servers

## **Key** (Experience Level)

• Expert • Intermediate O Novice

# **EDUCATION**

May, 2011

Enrolled | Theoretical Institute of Thermonuclear and Nuclear Studies
April, 2016 | M. Sc, Biophysics†

May, 2011 M. Sc, Nuclear Engineering & Engineering Physics

B. Sc, Nuclear Engineering

Managers / Advisors

Los Alamos National Laboratory Medical College of Wisconsin University of Wisconsin - Madison University of Wisconsin - Madison

Co-workers / Collaborators

†Thesis: "Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping: Exploratory Development and Initiation of Processing Pipelines"

# **AWARDS & HONORS**

June, 2019	LAAP Award	XTD-PRI, Los Alamos National Laboratory
August, 2017	SPOT Award	NEN-5, Los Alamos National Laboratory
May, 2016	Magna Cum Laude	Abstract, ISMRM Proceedings
May, 2014	Silver Medal	Student Poster Presentation, ISMRM Conference

# CLASSES & TRAININGS

May, 2018	Introduction to FLAG	Los Alamos New Mexico
May, 2016	MCNP6 Intermediate Workshop	Los Alamos New Mexico
May, 2015	CPR Certification Training	Milwaukee, Wisconsin
August, 2011	Dale Carnegie Training	Los Alamos, New Mexico
June, 2011	Introduction to Abaqus	Minneapolis, Minnesota
July, 2011	Introduction to Python Programming	Los Alamos, New Mexico
May, 2010	MCNP5 Beginner Workshop	Los Alamos, New Mexico

2009, 2010 | Exelon Scholarship University of Wisconsin - Madison

# REFERENCES

Wallage 19 / Navisors					
Roy Baty	rbaty@lanl.gov	505-667-9319	Dru Renner	dru@lanl.gov	505-667-4928
Leslie Wesler	lwesler@lanl.gov	505-665-3651	Mike Berry	mrberry@lanl.gov	505-667-7718
Rendell Carver	rc@lanl.gov	505-667-0121	Lucy Frey	lfrey@lanl.gov	505-667-7606
Brent Budden	budden@gmail.com	505-500-6652	Lori Pritchett-Sheets	lpritch@lanl.gov	505-665-6675
Karen Kelley	corzine@lanl.gov	505-667-8843	<b>Eugene Dougherty</b>	eed@lanl.gov	505-665-5068
Matt Griffin	griffin@lanl.gov	505-500-7010	James Tutt	jtutt@lanl.gov	505-695-3249

# **PUBLICATIONS & PRESENTATIONS**

- 1. Christopher Werner, Casey Anderson, and et. al. MCNP User's Manual Code Version 6.2 (LA-UR-17-29981). Oct. 2017
- 2. Casey Anderson and Gregg McKinney. "MCNP6 Built-in High Level Detector Responses". In: 2017 IEEE Nuclear Science Symposium and Medical Imaging Conference (Atlanta, Georgia). Oct. 2017,
- 3. <sup>‡</sup> Casey Anderson et al. "Neutron and Gamma Correlations using CGM in MCNP 6.2.0 (LA-UR-20353)". In: *Proceedings of the 27th American Nuclear Society Summer Meeting* (San Fransisco, California). 2017
- 4. § James Tutt and Gregg McKinney. "Speed and Memory Improvements to MCNP6 Delayed-Gamma Line Treatment (LA-UR-21050)". In: *Proceedings of the 27th American Nuclear Society Summer Meeting* (San Fransisco, California). 2017
- 5. <sup>‡</sup> Casey Anderson et al. "Delta-ray production in MCNP6.2.0 (LA-UR-16-25402)". In: *24th Conference on Applications of Accelerators in Research and Industry* (Forth Worth, Texas). Nov. 2016
- 6. <sup>‡</sup> James Tutt, Casey Anderson, and Gregg McKinney. "Background-Source Cosmic-Photon Elevation Scaling and Cosmic-Neutron/Photon Date Scaling in MCNP6 (LA-UR-16-24928)". In: *24th Conference on Applications of Accelerators in Research and Industry* (Forth Worth, Texas). Nov. 2016
- 7. James Tutt, Casey Anderson, and Gregg McKinney. "Delayed-Gamma Energy Biasing with Exact Energy Sampling in MCNP6.2.0 (LA-UR-16-24057)". In: *Proceedings of the 26th American Nuclear Society Winter Meeting* (Las Vegas, Nevada). Oct. 2016
- 8. || Casey Anderson et al. "Volume-Paracellated Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping". In: Proceedings of the International Society of Magnetic Resonance in Medicine 24th Conference (Singapore, Singapore). May 2016
- 9. <sup>‡</sup> Casey Anderson and Kevin Koch. "Volume-parcellated Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping of the Human Brain at 7T". in: 2015 Minnesota Workshop on High and Ultra-High Field Imaging (Minneapolis, Minnesota). Oct. 2015
- 10. Casey Anderson, Kimberley Pechman, and Kathleen Schmainda. "Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping to Assess Iron Levels in Rat Brain Tumors". In: *Proceedings of the International Society of Magnetic Resonance in Medicine 22nd Conference* (Milan, Italy). May 2014
- 11. Tim Goorley, Casey Anderson, and et. al. *Useful prompt radiation applications and capabilities with MCNP6 (LA-CP-12-00490)*. Nuclear Weapons Effects User Group. 2012
- 12. Tim Goorley, Jeff Bull, and et. al. "MCNP6 Efforts for EMP, atmospheric dispersal, and unstructured mesh tracking (LA-CP-01705)". In: *Proceedings of the Nuclear Explosives Design Physics Conference 2011* (Los Alamos National Laboratory, Los Alamos, New Mexico). Oct. 2012
- 13. Casey Anderson, Karen Kelley, and Tim Goorley. "Unstructured mesh human phantoms with MCNP". in: *Transactions of the American Nuclear Society* 106 (2012), pp. 50–51
- 14. ‡ Casey Anderson, Tim Goorley, and Karen Kelley. "Mesh Human Phantoms with MCNP (LA-UR-12-01307)". In: 2012 3DS Simulia Community Conference Proceedings (Providence, Rhode Island). May 2012, pp. 556–568

‡Presentation Included; §Presentation Only; | Magna Cum Laude

# **PATENTS**

i. Kevin Koch and Casey Anderson. System and method for localized processing of quantitative susceptibility maps in magnetic resonance imaging. WO Patent App. PCT/US2016/038,723. Dec. 2016. URL: https://www.google.com/patents/W02016209930A1?cl=en